mrooms.net 2016-04-19

# Privacy Policy - Moodlerooms

### **SECURITY POLICY SAFE HARBOR COMPLIANCE AND EU PRIVACY POLICY DIRECTIVE**

Effective Date 1st April, 2014

I. PURPOSE  
As part of Moodlerooms’ commitment to protect personal privacy, Moodlerooms adheres to the Safe Harbor Principles, administered by the United States Department of Commerce in consultation with the European Commission with respect to client personal information. Moodlerooms has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Moodlerooms’ certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/.

II. SCOPE  
This Policy is maintained by Moodlerooms Inc. on behalf of itself, its parent entity and its US and non-US subsidiaries and divisions (collectively, “Moodlerooms”), and applies to all current clients of Moodlerooms.

III. DEFINITIONS  
“Agent” means any third party that processes, collects, or uses Personal Information pursuant to the instructions of, and solely for the benefit of, Moodlerooms, or to which Moodlerooms, Inc. discloses Personal Information for use on its behalf.  
“Personal information”, means information that can directly or indirectly lead to the identification of a living person, such as an individual’s name, e-mail, or other identifying characteristic. Personal information does not include information that has been made anonymous, encoded or otherwise stripped of its identifiers, or information that is publicly available, unless combined with other non-public personal information.

IV. SEVEN PRINCIPALS OF SAFE HARBOR  
1\. NOTICE  
The following is our disclosure of how Moodlerooms, Inc. collects and uses personal information; any third parties to which we may disclose that information; how you can access your information and restrict our use of it; and how to contact us with any questions or complaints about how we use your information.  
Any personal information sent to us by our clients is used exclusively for the purposes and services for which we contracted. We do not share, transmit, rent or sell that information to any other parties.  
We may collect personal information such as name, title, firm, address, e-mail address, and survey results from individuals who have requested information from us or expressed interest in our products and services. You may provide this information to us electronically, over the Internet, or physically. Your personal information will be used by Moodlerooms, Inc., exclusively for the purpose of providing and improving service to you, or informing you of additional products and services which we think will be of interest to you.  
Other information gathered through this site is purely statistical, such as what Web pages are visited most often. This information is useful to Moodlerooms, Inc., and enables us not only to improve and upgrade our services but also to refine our product lines and marketing. This information is anonymous in nature.  
We do not collect sensitive personal information (e.g., personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, views or activities, social security benefits or information specifying the sex life of the individual or criminal or administrative proceedings) or receive sensitive personal information from any third parties.

2\. CHOICE  
If you request information from us, you will be given the choice at that time to opt out of receiving future communications from us on information, products, or services that may be of interest to you.  
If you have provided us with your personal information in the past, and you do not wish to receive further communications of information, products, or services from us, you can opt out, by sending an email to: unsubscribe@moodlerooms.com.  
If you provide personal information to us as part of a service we provide to you or your organization, we do not share, transmit, rent or sell that information to any third parties except as described herein.

3\. ONWARD TRANSFER  
Moodlerooms only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of Moodlerooms in the following limited circumstances:

Where Moodlerooms receives personal information from persons in the EU, Moodlerooms will use and disclose such information only in accordance with the purposes for which it was originally collected or in accordance with notices we might provide to such persons.

We provide personal information to offices, subcontractors or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf or providing the services. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.  
We have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request; (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof; (c) detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Moodlerooms, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.

Moodlerooms will provide notice and provide individuals with the opportunity to “opt out” if such personal information is to be disclosed to a third party or used for purposes incompatible with the purpose for which it was originally collected.

4\. SECURITY  
Moodlerooms employs considerable precautions within the company — including physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards — designed to secure the privacy of all personal information we retain, and protect it from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

Moodlerooms does not require or store any personal information from clients other than email address, name, phone numbers, fax numbers, business address, and contact name.

Moodlerooms Cookies – When you visit Moodlerooms, we send one or more cookies (a small file containing a string of characters) to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent.

However, some Moodlerooms features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. For more information on Moodlerooms cookies and the EU Privacy Directive, please see section V. of the security policy below.  
Log Information – When you use Moodlerooms services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

User Communications – When you send e-mail or other communication to Moodlerooms, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.

Other Sites – This Privacy Policy applies to all Web sites and services that are owned and operated by Moodlerooms. We do not exercise control over the site links from within our various services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you.

We restrict access to personal information to Moodlerooms employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution if they fail to meet these obligations.

5\. ACCESS OF RECORDS  
Upon an individual’s request, Moodlerooms will offer clients reasonable access to their personal information and will afford clients a reasonable opportunity to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate information. If a client would like to access personal information maintained by the Moodlerooms, the client should send an email to: security@moodlerooms.com

For security purposes, the individual may need to provide Moodlerooms with various pieces of personal information to process the request. Moodlerooms may limit or deny access to personal information where providing such access would be unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances or as otherwise permitted by the Safe Harbor Principles.

6\. DATA INTEGRITY

Moodlerooms will take reasonable measures to ensure that personal information is relevant for its intended use, reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current.

Some of our services have different procedures to access, correct or delete client personal information. We provide the details for these procedures in the specific privacy notices or FAQs for these services.

7\. ENFORCEMENT  
Moodlerooms, Inc., Safe Harbor Compliance Committee, is responsible for verifying that our Privacy Policy is accurate, comprehensive, prominently displayed, completely implemented, accessible, and in compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles. The committee is also responsible for employee training related to the Privacy Policy and periodic review to make sure the proper procedures and protections are in place.

Any questions or complaints regarding Moodlerooms, Inc., handling of personal information can be addressed by sending an email to: privacy@moodlerooms.com.

Any complaints or disputes that are not satisfactorily resolved by the Safe Harbor Compliance Committee can be referred to the European Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) for investigation and resolution. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint, or your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Moodlerooms, you may contact either the panel at ec-dppanel-secr@ec.europa.eu or individual EU DPAs (see http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/eu/index_en.htm).

Moodlerooms, reserves the right to update and revise this Privacy Policy at any time consistent with the Safe Harbor Principles. You can determine if this Privacy Policy has been revised since your last visit by referring to the “Effective Date of Current Policy” date at the top of this page. Your use of our Site constitutes your acceptance of the terms of the Privacy Policy as amended or revised by us, and you should therefore review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure that you are aware of its terms.

V. COOKIES AND PRIVACY INFORMATION FOR JOULE AND POWER  
1\. ABOUT COOKIES  
A cookie is a file issued from a website, Internet based application or Internet delivered content to a end user’s connected device (e.g. web browser, smartphone, etc). Cookies may be used to uniquely identify a user and they may be used to track individual preferences and other information about a web user. Moodlerooms products use this technology to provide secure learning experiences, track usage and manage application performance. Third party content may be embedded on pages within Moodlerooms products and may include cookies from the content issuer. See third party cookies (below) for more details. A visitor connecting to the website that hosts this product will be issued cookies that are strictly necessary for security and application performance.

2\. FIRST PARTY COOKIES AND RELATED TECHNOLOGIES  
Cookie: Moodle Login  
Cookie Name: MoodleSession, MoodleSessionTest, MoodleID

Purpose: “MoodleSession” is used to store the user’s session id. “MoodleID” is used for prepopulating the username in the login field.  
“MoodleSessionTest” is used to test whether cookies are working properly for the page, and does not contain any data.

Cookie: Alfresco  
Cookie Name: JSESSIONID  
Purpose: Stores the ID of the Alfresco session. Required for Single Sign-On into Alfresco.  
Cookie: PLD  
Cookie Name: pld  
Purpose: Used for storing the activity filter between page loads.

Cookie: SCORM  
Cookie Name: SCORMLoggingActive hide:SCORMitem  
Purpose: “SCORMLoggingActive” is used to toggle whether the user has enabled debugging for SCORM. “hide:SCORMitem” is used to store state information between page loads when an item has been toggled as hidden.

Cookie: Wiki  
Cookie Name: EWIKI_UP_NOSPAMBOT  
Purpose: Used to validate that the user is not a spam bot, and stores that information for subsequent posts.

3.THIRD PARTY COOKIES

Content, Blocks, Modules, Filters and other Tools used in conjunction with Moodlerooms products may install additional cookies on your computer. We have collected and noted items below for disclosure. These cookies are subject to privacy policies of the issuing site or service and not controlled by Moodlerooms or the institution operating Moodlerooms software.

Organizations using Moodlerooms products should examine the content provided and determine if this material is consistent with their privacy policies. If you do not agree with the use of cookies in the following manner, as well as outlined by the applicable organization which controls the cookie, do not use the applicable product.

Item: MS Live @ EDU  
Cookies: wls_AccessToken, wls_liveId, wls_AccessToken, wls_consentToken_cid, wls_RefreshToken, c_scope, c_error, c_error_description, c_accessToken, c_expiry, c_code, c_refreshToken, c_clientId, lca  
Moodlerooms Data Sharing: Description and Purpose: These cookies are essential to use in the operation of the MS Live @ EDU integration.  
Third Party and Privacy Policy: Contact Microsoft

Item: Mahara  
Cookies: mahara, viewaccess:X, mviewaccess:X, caccess:X  
Moodlerooms Data Sharing: Description and Purpose: The “mahara” cookie is used to store the user’s session id. The “access” cookies are used to pass the selected artifact between page loads.

Item: OU Blog  
Cookies: OUBLOG_CONFIRMED_COOKIE  
Moodlerooms Data Sharing: Description and Purpose: Used to validate that the user is not a spam bot, and stores that information for subsequent posts.

Item: Turnitin Direct  
Cookies: turnitintool_choice_user, turnitintool_choice_count  
Moodlerooms Data Sharing: Description and Purpose: Tracks the number of submissions per user.

4.STORAGE OF USER PREFERENCES AND PERSONAL INFORMATION  
Users Preferences and Personal Information Stored Locally on your Computer or Terminal Device  
This application stores user preferences and/or personal information on the terminal device or computer that accesses this product.

Item: Session & Login Information  
Description: This application stores your user session locally in a browser cookie (noted above). This cookie persists until you log out of the Moodlerooms application.

Potential for Disclosure to other Users: If you fail to log out of the Moodlerooms application and leave the terminal device without closing the entire browser application, this information could be used by other users of the same terminal device or computer.

Removal: Log out of the Moodlerooms Application.  
Users Preferences and Personal Information Stored on the Remote Server Supporting this Application

Item: User Directory Information  
Options: System Administrators may disable the user directory tool. End Users may modify the information disclosed from within the options under “Personal Information”

Item: Course Roster  
Options: System administrators and instructors may disable the course roster tool from individual courses or the entire application.

Item: Grades  
Item: Password  
Item: User Session  
Item: User Contributed Materials  
Description: Tests, Discussion Board Postings, Assignments, and other materials uploaded to the software  
Potential for Disclosure: Information may be shared with instructors, other course members and guests to the course consistent with the individual configuration settings of the course and instructor.

Requesting Removal of Private Information

To remove stored materials from this service contact your local institution.

Tracking Activities and Usage

This software monitors your usage as your interact with it. This information is collected and shared consistent with the privacy policies noted above. The laws governing such a disclosure vary, depending on where the server is stored and the application is being used. You are advised to consult counsel of our choice regarding applicable laws and regulations. Moodlerooms may attempt to limit the disclosure of this information consistent with Moodlerooms’ legal advice and our privacy policies.
